NIKOLA JOVANOVIC FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

202.210.9355 | nikola4work@gmail.com | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>My Portfolio</u>
Arlington, VA 22201



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

UX/UI design-thinking, responsive web design and creation are my passions. Delighting users by creating UX/UI experiences that are inspiring, engaging, and memorable are what drive me and motivate me to do more. Experienced in Front-End and Back-End Technologies including: JavaScript/jQuery | CSS | HTML | Bootstrap | MySQL | MongoDB | Handlebars as well as REACT. Formerly a professional basketball player who brings a strong sense of teamwork, collaboration, diligence, leadership, and determination to meet and exceed the mission at-hand. I am focused and deadline oriented. I am extremely passionate about approaching programming and design challenges from different angles and collaborating with others to create value-driven web applications and products that delight users and keep them coming back. Being part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team building products that drive true value and increase user-adoption are truly inspiring to me.

KEY CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

•	Professional Basketball Player in Belgium	•	Graduated from George Washington University School of
			Professional Development with an A+ in Full Stack Web
			Development

Launched my own online Web Development Business and was Lead UX/UI Designer

KEY COMPETENCIES

RET COMPETENCIES	OWIFE LENGIES			
Responsive web design	 Front-end and back-end web development 			
Project Management	 Product Development & Conceptualization 			
Wire Frame Design	UX/UI Design Thinking			
 Leadership & Team Collaboration 	Excellent & Engaging communicator			

CAREER HISTORY

COMPANY	TITLE ROLE	DATES
LingoLabs	Lead UX/UI Designer	02/24/2020 to Present
Nazca Mochica Peruvian Restaurant	Manager	10/04/2016 to 02/01/2020
1209 N Taft Street LLC	General Manager	11/22/2014 to Present

February 2020 to Present

Lead UX/UI Designer: LingoLabs

- Gathering and evaluating user requirements, in collaboration with product managers and engineers.
- Illustrating design ideas using storyboards, process flows and sitemaps
- Designing graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs, widgets as well as many other UI components
- Building navigation components
- Build page navigation buttons and search fields
- Develop UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function, look and feel like
- Create original graphic designs (e.g.: images, sketches and tables)
- Prepare and present rough drafts to internal teams and key stakeholders
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems (e.g.: responsiveness)
- Conduct layout adjustments and changes based on user feedback
- Adhere to style standards and branding look and feel
- Utilizing design software and wireframe tools
- · Team spirit winner; strong communication skills and always willing to collaborate with team members

October 2016 To February 2020

Manager: Nazca Mochica Peruvian Cuisine

- Coordinating daily restaurant management operations
- Overseeing the delivery of superior foods and beverages and maximizing customer service and satisfaction
- Identifying new business models to generate new revenue streams for clients in the digital economy.
- Responding efficiently and accurately to customer requirements and/or complaints
- Responsible for leading all the aspects of the business and delivering high quality menus, products and services

NIKOLA JOVANOVIC FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

202.210.9355 | nikola4work@gmail.com | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>My Portfolio</u> Arlington, VA 22201



- Responsible for maintaining and increasing revenues
- Motivating, training and mentoring staff
- Ensuring efficient restaurant operations, as well as maintaining high levels of production, productivity and customerservice standards
- Leveraged management skills and optimized both the front and back of house by implementing software and new workflows
- Regularly reviewed product quality and researched the market place for alternative and better vendors and service providers
- Appraise staff performance, provided feedback and devised training and mentoring to ensure continued improvement and professional development
- Estimated future revenues, areas of growth and revenue models
- Controlled and oversee operational costs
- Promoted the brand using social platforms and other marketing channels

November 2014 To Present

General Manager: 1209 N Taft Street LLC

- Implement financial and operational initiatives to increase profitability and cut costs
- Inspect facilities and implemented maintenance programs and schedules
- Negotiate leases, contracts and advised on changes related to amendments in policy
- Project management of renovations, contractors and maintenance work
- Evaluate market conditions and prices when undertaking new contractual agreements
- Research and investigated service providers, conducted back round searches on new tenants prior to executing contracts and located reliable insurance firms
- Identify opportunities and developed strategies to enhance the financial performance of the properties
- Conduct marketing and outreach campaigns to attract new lessees and tenants

LANGUAGES

English, Serbian, and conversational Spanish

TECHNOLOGIES (Click here to see my Portfolio)

HTML	CSS	Bootstrap
JavaScript	Node.js	Handlebars
MongoDB	MySQL	jQuery
React.js	Data Structures	Heroku
Aiax	Algorithms	Responsive Design

EDUCATION

- Bachelor's Degree in Marketing: Higher Business School of Professional Studies Belgrade, Serbia 2015
- Bachelor's of Science in AOS Operations Systems: Union Nikola Tesla Belgrade, Serbia 09.2020
- NYACK-New York's Christian College-School of Business, Leadership and Business Administration 2016 Bachelor's Equivalency Degree in Marketing and Languages
- Full Stack Web Development: George Washington University Washington, D.C. 2020